all right we reached a part in Nam rim
where they talk about special qualities
of each of the jewels three jewels and
Rupert capers ship and gone there comes
a dog
this is part of your vow to take refuge
by thinking about cool things about the
three jobs okay so here comes a list of
six cool things
there's many but here's six number 110
Enoch Europe in Capernaum means cool
things about the three jewels just by by
destination by the qualities that they
have son gaining will return to remember
Tom to bikini Chen ent Buddhist the
coolest thing about them is that they're
Buddhist that's what he said okay
challenge any intention to check on
Jackie nickel congee kalmykia chamber
Seba they see the nature of all things
directly in Tibetan is called Jimbo who
knows what Jambo means jumbo means
making like okay unclosed just stay see
reality make it really ok it's also used
for uncooked vegetables I don't know why
okay Debra Sigma challenge so the word
in Tibetan for Buddha is well or one of
them is Sangay or Chun Chiu enlightened
minister called Chun - then he wants to
explain the word Chun which is bya ng
young child Shiva katayama
carton means condone or cotton means
when monks practice singing out loud
the the prayers that they're supposed to
learn okay and we spend I don't know an
hour - every day
memorizing prayers like the prayer we
use for the for the border prayer so
that's one that my Lama made me memorize
so then it's nice because you have those
prayers in your head all the time and
they're just repeating in your head all
the time like my trail or when manjushri
is talking in your head all day long so
it's nice - it's a nice custom to
memorize things in yoga what's the word
for memorize for the ayah you know it's
in the first chapter and people
mistranslated as self-knowledge or
something like that it doesn't the word
does never anything to do with that it
means to come down which means memorize
things you can start with the sixth
graces the sixth fluid prayers those are
very holy some from Biagio gaming
sometimes I got you know some about some
kapa that's a nice thing my mama made me
start with little prayers and then later
he would throw a hundred pages at me and
say memorized but you could start with
something so you start with those person
okay cotton gel and like John wait on
you so when you get really good at
something like I don't know I'm gonna
tell us about your design time explosion
I mean you know there could be a period
if you did I guess about you know you
like you just get used to it it's called
junk so Charlie's mastered when the
student can recite the prayer quickly
it's called junk it's one meaning of
cheong okay Tom we turn a profit on
topic our chamber to Pilate torture and
the Buddhist understanding is jump okay
so we call them Chung - okay that's one
explanation of junk okay so John can
mean well practiced okay and Britta's
well practice
I've seen all all great knowledge as
they have now Dharma Chinese language
and bjbj magenta this was one of the
meditations you had and they're almost
the defining feature of the Dharma is
that it's the footprint left by a Buddha
in this world okay the Dharma is the
footprint left by a Buddha in this world
okay
Jen by Jo means the fine fruits of their
journey here okay
Dayoung some education Jim Corcoran are
for example when the Buddha turned the
wheel of the Dharma the first time how
many times did he turn the wheel
yes three and those are really just
three different periods in his lifetime
that he was turning the wheel and and
what's interesting is he contradicted
himself each time okay first time he
said everything exists by itself second
time he said nothing exists by itself
then somebody asked him well first you
said everything's respecto then you said
nothing exist by itself what do you mean
then then he gave the third turning of
the wheel which is to explain what I
really meant and what I didn't really
mean and he wrote a book called what I
really meant
it's called sandy near Luciana Sutra and
I think it's exciting that we're we're
creating a team with Stanley and MIT for
American and Chinese translators to work
together and translate a very great
commentary on that Sutra by master UN
sir who was a student of Schwinn some
who who spent 17 years in India bringing
the books
back to to China okay so I think it's
exciting that we're we have a plan to
translate a debated books of his work
you know and I think it's cool the
subject of that work is what did the
Buddha really mean
which of the three turning of the wheel
was correct and which was not correct
okay why can he teach three different
things yeah according to the students
okay
like if you're giving a talk to a bunch
of business people you can say nothing's
really empty and then when you get to
Diamond Mountain and you can say what
you really want to say you can say
everything's empty okay all right I
think that somebody season on the
internet you have to fiddle between the
two okay Jim Corcoran a lot a somber
Gillett own lumps all cheering fuckabish
him the first time the Buddha taught the
Dharma in Solna right in the Deer Park
we recently had a chance some of our
students are a chance to visit there and
[Music]
he had five students who were the five
yeah the mommy tiger and the four cups
that he gave his body to in his previous
life when he gave them his body he said
you're going to be my first students in
when I become Buddha I also do it with
McDonald's french fries I'll go outside
with my french fries which is the only
thing I can eat at McDonald's and I'll
throw it to the birds and I'll say if
you eat it you're going to be in my
superior when I become emunah and then
they're like so she gave back ever seen
Meg I've said machine you want the chip
off so there was a certain presentation
he made to those five which was designed
for them okay the four truths
presentation later he did presentations
on the twelve links and and then
emptiness to continental
okay by the way there's a famous
description of how he repeated the four
to three times and during the first
teaching to those five people and each
of them had a different reaction and so
I thought you might like to hear it okay
so I went and got it from the Ovid mi
chiamo exudation or like David Tate when
the buddha repeated the four truths
three times
kun jacobina so there's one student
named Kenya and you're going to meet him
in the you're gonna meet him in the
kamila Sheila teaching okay
if I'm not mistaken he was the guide
cutting off the buddha's fingers in his
past knife okay but we'll check
okay so gardenia is the smartest one of
the five maybe he's the mommy tiger I
don't know Kabini atolan the first time
the Buddha talked for truth he achieved
the direct perception emptiness okay
shangela's allah and the other four got
to the second path which is called the
path of preparation they understood the
pen
one guy slanting is directly for people
got the pen okay got it
definitely taken shell kodi neeya
kilogram lon the second time he repeated
the fortress calvini a-- reached path of
habituation the fourth path okay gum
lancashire shakeela : k and the other
four had the director section emptiness
okay so by the end of the second
repetition of the four truth all five
had seen emptiness directly those were
the good old days okay damp assume they
say Risha gardenia Gillan we love love
and on the third repetition Kenya
reached our heart he reached the fifth
path which is the path of no more
learning and shakeila coma and the other
four reached the path of habituation the
fourth path character by your jessilee
to a mistake okay okay now let's go back
to the laundry room we have three
minutes they always talk about the
reaction of the five and I always forget
what it was so now you can remind me
okay
again to get you to do beat any general
what's the kind of the defining quality
of their song that's a so far we are a
person who knows all things and then
their footprint in the world is the
Dharma jewel and then the people who
practice that Dharma jewel are called
so the job that's the definition of
seunga they practice the dharma jewel
okay that's their job to make it kept on
me and then there's a distinction of
Tinley tin layer we talked about the
other day
it means the gaze of a Buddha holy deeds
okay son gave me a note about putting a
Buddhist job is to teach okay why why I
have to teach we talked about it yeah
it's all it's some meditation we had
number two you know that's the only way
they can help us anything okay
they can't move seeds into our mind okay
they have to teach us and we have to
make our own seeds that's a tenant of
Buddhism that's a basic fact of Buddhism
you have to do the work yourself Lama
can teach you they knew how to do the
work yourself okay because the mama
because you made kama by doing things
and watching yourself do them that's how
your plena see and hear but surely for
example in Capuchin so the British job
is to teach the Dharma snob is to help
you get rid of problems that you have
okay I'm just once again give me Cheney
on Sonam I like this because he
describes the job of the Sangha as
changing on some long bay and it means
they should be they should set an
example for other people that's the job
of the Sun okay and you know we spent a
lot of time this year trying to figure
out our teacher training program in
Sedona and you're welcome to come by the
way you have a three times a year
BCI teacher training program we're going
to add an ACI teacher training program
if anyone's interested
and we so we're waiting to ask people
but I think what we realized is that the
best way to train someone to be a
teacher is to convince them to be a good
example for other people it's not so
much what you say look and talk and talk
and talk you know parent knows the kids
won't follow what you say the kids will
copy exactly what you do and it's this
made for people like me who teach for
many years to see people follow exactly
what we do instead of what we told them
to do okay then the teacher realizes oh
I have to practice what I preach I have
to be a good example the job of the
Sangha is to be an example okay and and
that's here so that's based on teacher
training core principle that the way to
be a teacher is to be an example this
guy teaches how to be successful we
advertise inner and outer success inside
you're supposed to be clean and peaceful
and you know well mannered and then
outside you're supposed to be
financially independent and and have
good health and sweet relationships with
people and and so when people ask us
what's the most important thing I have
to know to be a teacher
we'll say blue those things basic we're
teaching a method of success if you're
not successful it looks suspicious
maybe the system doesn't work okay or
maybe you shouldn't be teaching because
you haven't done it yet okay all right
David topics a shame to Daytona when
other people see a person who has
reached inner and outter success here's
where it comes from okay
de la pista then they will follow you
they will copy you if you got a very
very beautiful apartment by visiting old
ladies at the nursing home maybe you
went with the Singapore group then
obviously other people will try you see
other people will copy you all right
Shelley Daytona Villa and Jupiter
myung-gil
wrote kappa and in that way you can
really help people rock Japan itself
people
gilma remember to attend a channel so
really he says you can define the Sangha
as people who enjoy doing nice things
for other people
okay garol octo okay tinleigh that's
what the sanghas job is is to do nice
things for other people and set an
example okay that's all we have time for
right now but how about a question when
we start again because we're a little
bit tight today